<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2025-06-30T12:07:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Not Every Week Is a Big Launch (And That's Okay)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/not-every-week-is-a-big-launch-and-that-s-okay/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/not-every-week-is-a-big-launch-and-that-s-okay/</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T12:07:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-30T13:59:42-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In startup land, there&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to glorify the big launch, the shiny new feature, the growth spike, the viral moment. But the truth? Most weeks don&amp;rsquo;t look like that. Some weeks are just plain messy. And that&amp;rsquo;s when the real work happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I set out with a clear goal: ship a major onboarding improvement for &lt;a href="https://boxboard.io/?utm_source=jasonblog&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=article"&gt;BoxBoard&lt;/a&gt;. On paper, it was a straightforward win. But by midweek, I realized I was knee-deep in server configurations, struggling with AWS limits, and reevaluating tools I thought were locked in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what happened, and what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;🛠 When a “Simple” Tool Change Becomes a Full DevOps Saga&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="code-e9396b21.webp" alt="Developer working late at night debugging server configurations and AWS setup issues" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been juggling Google Analytics and Mixpanel to track user behavior and marketing leads, but they never gave me the visibility I wanted. So I decided to explore PostHog, a more customizable, all-in-one alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured I&amp;rsquo;d self-host it on AWS for control and cost savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoiler: it did not go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The install stalled repeatedly. EC2 configs weren&amp;rsquo;t enough. The server kept maxing out, and I found myself rebuilding the stack more than once just to maybe get the dashboard running. By the third rebuild, I finally stopped and asked: “Why am I burning a week on this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pivoted to PostHog&amp;rsquo;s cloud version and got things up quickly. And it&amp;rsquo;s already proving useful, especially for tracking where my marketing leads are coming from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;🧱 Shipping Foundations (Even If Nobody Sees Them)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="itterate-708ad5d3.webp" alt="Iterative development process showing multiple rounds of testing and refinement for BoxBoard features" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond analytics, I shipped a new invite flow for gyms, now they can onboard members directly via CSV upload or email invite. It&amp;rsquo;s not a glamorous feature, but it&amp;rsquo;s a game-changer for busy gym owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I wanted to ship more, that one feature turned out to be several days of work: testing, UX polishing, and edge case handling. You know… software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;📏 What I Learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="loading-31bda24c.webp" alt="Loading screen or progress indicator representing the patience required during development setbacks" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estimate x3 for unfamiliar tech.&lt;/strong&gt; I asked AI to help forecast time on my EC2 setup, but underestimated just how many edge cases I&amp;rsquo;d hit. When you&amp;rsquo;re outside your usual zone, pad your timeline more than you think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let frustration snowball.&lt;/strong&gt; Midweek, I caught myself getting cranky. That&amp;rsquo;s when I stepped back, reframed the goal (“test PostHog” not “perfect PostHog setup”), and found a way forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflect before you spiral.&lt;/strong&gt; I try to journal weekly. Some weeks feel like a slog in the moment, but when I zoom out, I see progress. And even if it&amp;rsquo;s not flashy, laying solid foundations is still a win.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;🎯 A Word for Fellow Solo Builders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your week didn&amp;rsquo;t result in a splashy demo or viral post, that&amp;rsquo;s okay. Progress often looks like wrangling a bug, refining infrastructure, or rethinking a process. It looks like momentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when next week starts, sprinkle in some &amp;ldquo;candy&amp;rdquo;, the fun, energizing work that reminds you why you&amp;rsquo;re doing this. You&amp;rsquo;ve earned it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Shipping Fast, Breaking Less: Managing Tech Debt in the AI Era</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/shipping-fast-breaking-less-managing-tech-debt-in-the-ai-era/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/shipping-fast-breaking-less-managing-tech-debt-in-the-ai-era/</id>
    <published>2025-06-05T10:46:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-05T11:04:27-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt; AI can ship fast. Like… &lt;em&gt;really fast&lt;/em&gt;. But if you don’t layer in structure, intent, and human refinement, that speed can come at a steep cost.&lt;br&gt;
Move fast—but pay your future self by building in check-ins, code patterns, and feedback loops from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. “Vibe Coding” Is Real—and Risky&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, we’re seeing people with no traditional coding background &lt;em&gt;vibe&lt;/em&gt; their way into working apps.&lt;br&gt;
That’s a good thing—for speed, creativity, and access.&lt;br&gt;
But…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI is often great at making something &lt;strong&gt;work&lt;/strong&gt;, not making it &lt;strong&gt;right&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you rely purely on a single AI tool to generate your code (especially without proper structure), you’ll likely pay the price later:
- In feature collisions
- In unscalable patterns
- In &amp;ldquo;where-the-heck-is-this&amp;rdquo; code chaos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="good-vibes-1ebfa732.webp" alt="Good Vibes only" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Speed ≠ Sloppiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the pattern I use when building fast features for BoxBoard while still keeping my codebase clean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;✅ Small updates only&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though AI wants to do &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; at once, I try to &lt;strong&gt;chunk my changes&lt;/strong&gt;. One idea per commit, even if it’s minor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;✅ Refactor checkpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a set of commits, I take a beat and do &lt;strong&gt;human-driven polish&lt;/strong&gt;:
- Break long views into partials or components
- Normalize CSS
- Re-structure messy logic
- Apply naming consistency&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;✅ Design first, refine later&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For views and layout:
- I let the AI &lt;strong&gt;scaffold&lt;/strong&gt; the initial pass
- Then I &lt;strong&gt;refine layout and CSS patterns&lt;/strong&gt; manually&lt;br&gt;
Especially if it’s custom. Tailwind-based React projects? AI does great. Custom-markup Rails views? I take the lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Use AI Tools as a &lt;em&gt;Team&lt;/em&gt;, Not a Single Brain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re just throwing code into one AI, you’ll miss the power of &lt;em&gt;roles&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Here’s how I think about it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Builder AI&lt;/strong&gt; – ChatGPT or Cursor helps write initial logic&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviewer AI&lt;/strong&gt; – Claude or even another ChatGPT instance checks for structure, naming, or optimization&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me (Human)&lt;/strong&gt; – Guides structure, product vision, UX thinking, and subtle polish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach prevents bad code from compounding. One AI builds. One reviews. I lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="code-dbce18c2.webp" alt="Code Refactor" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Add Rules When You Find the Gaps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI learns from you—if you train it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I find myself &lt;strong&gt;fighting&lt;/strong&gt; an AI-generated pattern (especially with CSS or file placement), I create new rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❌ &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t create random files in &lt;code&gt;app/assets&lt;/code&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
✅ &amp;ldquo;Use &lt;code&gt;app/frontend/components&lt;/code&gt; for reusable JS and CSS.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
✅ &amp;ldquo;All new views should use the &lt;code&gt;BoxboardLayout&lt;/code&gt; and follow X pattern.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep a &lt;strong&gt;living prompt primer&lt;/strong&gt; and reference it in each session.&lt;br&gt;
I’ve even created &lt;strong&gt;diagrams&lt;/strong&gt; of my folder structure and included that as visual input to help the AI better understand the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5. AI Is Speed. You Are Structure.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to think about it is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;AI Strengths&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Your Role&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rapid scaffolding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Set the vision&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Syntax + boilerplate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shape the structure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Suggestions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Define the rules&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Getting unstuck&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Know when to pause and rethink&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;6. Final Thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes—AI can help you ship a working MVP in a day.&lt;br&gt;
But &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; is going to pay the tech debt bill eventually.&lt;br&gt;
That someone might be you&amp;hellip; in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So set the structure early. Build fast. Refactor often.&lt;br&gt;
And treat your AI tools like junior engineers—great at execution, but always in need of guidance and a good product lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Got your own rules or ways to avoid AI-induced chaos?&lt;br&gt;
Let me know what’s working (or not) in your workflow—DM me or connect over &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasoncypret"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://x.com/jasoncypret"&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How I Orchestrate AI Tools Like a Product Team</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/how-i-orchestrate-ai-tools-like-a-product-team/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/how-i-orchestrate-ai-tools-like-a-product-team/</id>
    <published>2025-05-29T11:27:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-29T11:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t wait for one tool that can do it all—build your own AI squad and assign each role. You&amp;rsquo;ll move faster, stay in control, and spend more time on the parts of product development that actually excite you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;One AI to rule them all? That&amp;rsquo;s a trap.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s waiting for &lt;em&gt;the one&lt;/em&gt;: a magical AI tool that designs, writes, codes, and deploys while you sip cold brew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not how I work. And honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I want it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ve found a much more realistic—and scalable—approach: &lt;strong&gt;treat each AI tool like a teammate.&lt;/strong&gt; Give it a specific role. Let it shine in the right part of the workflow. Stay involved in the things only you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how I orchestrate my &amp;ldquo;AI team&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I kick off a new feature or idea, I think like a PM first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;ChatGPT = Solution Architect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always start by thinking like a product manager:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a user, I want [X] so that [Y].&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I describe the current context—what&amp;rsquo;s in place, what&amp;rsquo;s missing, and what the desired experience should feel like. I plug that into ChatGPT (or Claude) and ask it to play prompt engineer:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Turn this user story and background into a detailed technical brief.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT excels here: it identifies edge cases, suggests data models, and sometimes even catches things I missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll often prime the model with screenshots, style guidelines, or example interactions from Dribbble or my own app. This is where I shape the big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Cursor = Senior Developer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I have a solid brief, I move into the codebase with Cursor.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursor helps me:
- Find relevant files across my Rails monolith
- Scaffold new components or endpoints
- Write tests I&amp;rsquo;d otherwise forget
- Catch inconsistencies or unhandled logic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works best when I&amp;rsquo;ve already thought through the logic. Think of Cursor like a skilled dev—you still need to lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Me = Product/UX Lead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where human me steps in:
- Review and refine UI in &lt;strong&gt;Figma&lt;/strong&gt;
- Pull references and patterns from the design system
- Spot where brand, voice, or user flow needs love
- Time-box feedback loops so I don&amp;rsquo;t endlessly iterate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal isn&amp;rsquo;t perfection on pass one—it&amp;rsquo;s momentum. Good enough is often great enough to ship, test, and then evolve later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why orchestration beats over-reliance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you assign roles, a few good things happen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Benefit&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Why it matters&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each tool stays in its lane&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ChatGPT thinks big. Cursor stays close to code. Figma keeps the UI grounded.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t lose control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not handing the whole project to a single black box. You&amp;rsquo;re staying in the loop.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can upgrade in pieces&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Swap Claude in for ChatGPT? Easy. Test new AI dev tools? Go for it. You&amp;rsquo;re modular.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can scale faster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Each tool adds leverage. Together, they 10x you—without replacing you.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pain points and workarounds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, even orchestration has bumps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lost context?&lt;/strong&gt; → Save prompt templates. Include links to brand, design, and past work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI goes rogue?&lt;/strong&gt; → Define &amp;ldquo;do not use&amp;rdquo; libraries, patterns, or file paths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Too many options?&lt;/strong&gt; → Time-box decisions. If I&amp;rsquo;m stuck more than 30 mins, I zoom out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Recent &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; moment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been avoiding a Stripe subscription bug—nervous it might mess with money.&lt;br&gt;
But this time, I walked through it with Cursor + ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reviewed docs, explored the code, scaffolded a fix, and tested it—all in a single focused afternoon. No panic. No rabbit hole. Just fast, accurate work with great backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Advice I&amp;rsquo;d give a junior teammate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re just getting started with this stack, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;d say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn what makes a good user story.&lt;/strong&gt; Break ideas down into small, testable pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use different tools for different hats.&lt;/strong&gt; Treat ChatGPT like a PM, Cursor like a dev, and Figma like your UI pair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create chat &amp;ldquo;roles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; One conversation might be your solution architect. Another is a tech writer. Another is your QA. Label them. Revisit them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clearer &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are, the better your tools can support you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Final thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t wait for one tool to do it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orchestrate the tools you&amp;rsquo;ve already got.&lt;br&gt;
Assign them roles.&lt;br&gt;
Stay in the loop.&lt;br&gt;
And use your best human skills—judgment, taste, curiosity—to guide the whole show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="ai-itteration-32bff9f6.webp" title="Illustration: AI tools orbiting a laptop, representing orchestrated collaboration between ChatGPT, Cursor, Claude, and Figma" alt="Orchestration illustration" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Got your own AI tool stack or orchestration tips? I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what&amp;rsquo;s working for you—DM me or reply on &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jasoncypret/"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://x.com/jasoncypret"&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Your Job Isn't Gone—Your Job Description Is</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/your-job-isn-t-gone-your-job-description-is/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/your-job-isn-t-gone-your-job-description-is/</id>
    <published>2025-05-21T09:59:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-21T11:43:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;tl;dr *&lt;/em&gt;AI isn&amp;rsquo;t coming for your job—it&amp;rsquo;s coming for the &lt;em&gt;version&lt;/em&gt; of your
job that hasn&amp;rsquo;t evolved. The people who thrive will wield AI to stretch
beyond a single specialty and stitch together value in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1 Why the &amp;ldquo;single-lane&amp;rdquo; career is fading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in my career I wore tidy labels—designer, then front-end dev, then UX
leader. That worked when tooling friction kept each craft in its silo.&lt;br&gt;
Today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text-to-image tools draft logos in seconds.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code copilots stub features while you sip coffee.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLMs brainstorm 100 marketing angles before lunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result:&lt;/strong&gt; what used to be an expensive hand-off chain is now a solo flight
with AI riding shotgun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2 Four hats, one (busy) week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outputs below all happened in &lt;em&gt;small pockets of time&lt;/em&gt; during the same week.
AI handled the grunt work; I played editor-in-chief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2.1 Logo exploration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="logos-64fbb791.webp" title="Logo concepts generated with Midjourney + Figma tweaks" alt="AI-assisted logo sheet" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prompt:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Generate abstract logomarks for a real-estate market-comparison app
called &amp;lsquo;SmartComps&amp;rsquo;; style: bold, geometric.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I iterated on the best mark in Figma, refined curves, and exported variants.
Hands-on time: ≈ 25 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2.2 Landing-page draft&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="boxboard-lp-fcf633aa.webp" title="Landing page scaffolded with Lovable + Cursor and styled in Tailwind" alt="AI-generated landing page" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workflow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lovable&lt;/strong&gt; to spark layout &amp;amp; copy ideas.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cursor&lt;/strong&gt; to translate the best concept into React/Tailwind code.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick polish pass for brand tone, then push to a preview branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; front-end boxes checked in under an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2.3 Marketing-idea factory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="ideas-cebd094b.webp" title="Notion board filled by n8n + OpenAI" alt="List of AI-generated content ideas" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;n8n&lt;/strong&gt; flow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cron trigger (Monday 08:00)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postgres &lt;code&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; to avoid duplicates&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenAI: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Give me 10 *&lt;/em&gt;new** social posts for BoxBoard&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;*&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert rows back into &lt;code&gt;marketing_ideas&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slack DM the top idea to me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five nodes = one less weekly chore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2.4 Code-enhancement sprint&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="code-1a1f9147.webp" title="Cursor.ai pair-programming session" alt="Code diff with AI suggestions" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cursor.ai nudged me through test stubs, edge-case handling, and a small
refactor—more output, less keyboard time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 Patterns I&amp;rsquo;m leaning on&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Pattern&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Why it works&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prompt → Draft → Human polish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AI gets ~80 %; I inject taste &amp;amp; domain nuance.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One source of truth&lt;/strong&gt; (Postgres)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Multiple &amp;ldquo;agents&amp;rdquo; read/write without spreadsheet chaos.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Componentized thinking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Each task is a Lego brick; future flows can chain them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4 From specialist to &amp;ldquo;Swiss-army-knife&amp;rdquo; teammate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not abandoning UX leadership; I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;augmenting&lt;/em&gt; it. The evolving baseline
stack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core craft&lt;/strong&gt; (design, dev, PM, etc.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prompt literacy&lt;/strong&gt; (coax the best from LLMs)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workflow design&lt;/strong&gt; (thinking in nodes, triggers, data stores)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapid experimentation mindset&lt;/strong&gt; (ship → measure → tweak)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies will prize people who glide across that spectrum—handoff overhead is
now effectively free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5 Try it yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pick a dormant skill&lt;/strong&gt; you haven&amp;rsquo;t touched in years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draft a micro-project&lt;/strong&gt; that takes &amp;lt; 1 hr with AI help.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ship&lt;/strong&gt;—even if it&amp;rsquo;s rough.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflect:&lt;/strong&gt; What felt slow? Automate that next.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where could &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; add value once the boilerplate melts away?&lt;br&gt;
Share a win (or face-plant) in the comments—let&amp;rsquo;s trade notes. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks for reading—now go make something weird (with a little help from the
machines).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tiny Agents, Not AGI: Building a 5-Node Marketing-Idea Generator in n8n</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/tiny-agents-not-agi-building-a-5-node-marketing-idea-generator-in-n8n/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/tiny-agents-not-agi-building-a-5-node-marketing-idea-generator-in-n8n/</id>
    <published>2025-05-14T11:32:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-14T12:25:04-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;quot;Agents&amp;quot; sound intimidating, but the smallest useful one I&amp;rsquo;ve built
fits neatly into a five-node n8n workflow that runs every Monday, creates
&lt;em&gt;fresh&lt;/em&gt; marketing ideas for BoxBoard, and stores them for later use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. Wait—what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an &amp;ldquo;agent&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve opened LinkedIn or Product Hunt in the last year, you&amp;rsquo;ve heard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our platform now supports &lt;strong&gt;agents&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, most of those agents are just &lt;strong&gt;workflows&lt;/strong&gt; that contain at
least &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; step where an LLM makes a decision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trigger&lt;/strong&gt; – something kicks the flow off&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LLM call&lt;/strong&gt; – the &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo; step&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action&lt;/strong&gt; – data is stored, sent, or transformed&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. 90 % plumbing, 10 % AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. My use-case: weekly marketing inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Monday I used to spend 20 minutes brainstorming LinkedIn ideas for
BoxBoard. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely the kind of low-leverage chore automations love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The &lt;em&gt;initial&lt;/em&gt; 4-node proof-of-concept&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cron Trigger&lt;/strong&gt; – fires at 08:00 on Mondays&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenAI&lt;/strong&gt; – &amp;ldquo;Give me 10 marketing post ideas for BoxBoard.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code&lt;/strong&gt; – turn the JSON into rows&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postgres Insert&lt;/strong&gt; – save into &lt;code&gt;marketing_ideas&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worked! But after week two the model repeated itself—classic LLM amnesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The &lt;em&gt;current&lt;/em&gt; 5-node version&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Screenshot below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cron Trigger&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postgres Select&lt;/strong&gt; – pull last week&amp;rsquo;s ideas&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenAI&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Give me 10 *&lt;/em&gt;new** ideas not found in this list&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;*&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code&lt;/strong&gt; – format rows&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postgres Insert&lt;/strong&gt; – write the fresh set&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="simple-n8n-workflow-c2115a68.webp" title="Five-node n8n flow that generates new marketing ideas and stores them in Postgres" alt="n8n workflow: cron → Postgres select → OpenAI → code → Postgres insert" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Why Postgres and not Sheets / Airtable?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deduping &amp;amp; filtering&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;code&gt;SELECT DISTINCT&lt;/code&gt; is trivial in SQL.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joins&lt;/strong&gt; – later I can enrich ideas with performance metrics.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability&lt;/strong&gt; – when this grows into a full &amp;ldquo;marketing squad&amp;rdquo; of flows,
I already have a relational backbone.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rails front-end&lt;/strong&gt; – I surface the table in a lightweight admin panel; no
zap-to-sheet gymnastics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use whatever datastore fits your stack, but SQL saves future you a refactor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Extending the agent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add a Slack node&lt;/strong&gt; – DM myself the top idea every Monday morning.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hook into Notion&lt;/strong&gt; – auto-create a content brief with tone &amp;amp; target
audience filled in.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback loop&lt;/strong&gt; – after a post goes live, write engagement stats back to
Postgres so the next prompt can prioritize high-performing themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5. Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Small is beautiful.&lt;/em&gt; An &amp;ldquo;agent&amp;rdquo; can start with one LLM call and still
deliver real value.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think like a PM.&lt;/em&gt; Break ambitious ideas into tiny shippable tasks; wire
them; iterate.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data matters.&lt;/em&gt; Choosing a real database early unlocks smarter prompts and
future automation layers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where could a five-node flow erase your Monday busywork?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Questions or war stories about your own tiny agents?&lt;br&gt;
Ping me on Twitter—always happy to swap notes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI and the Future of UX: Key Takeaways from Gartner Day 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gartner-2024-day-2/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gartner-2024-day-2/</id>
    <published>2024-10-22T16:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2025-03-31T17:20:32-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gartner 2024 Day 2: Exploring AI, the Future, and the Human Experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today marked the second day of the Gartner Symposium, and I managed to sit through six insightful talks. AI was once again a central theme, with topics ranging from its practical applications to far-reaching futuristic visions. While I’m starting to feel a bit of AI overload, there were standout sessions that left me thinking about the potential of AI in ways I hadn’t considered before. My favorite talks were those that encouraged a vision of the future beyond today’s immediate AI implementations and into the realms of space, robots, and transforming our daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick recap of the sessions I attended:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interview with Jensen Huang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gartner’s Top Strategic Predictions for 2025 and Beyond: Riding the AI Whirlwind by Daryl Plummer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maverick Research: Being Human 2045 by Marty Resnick&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Executive Guide to AI Governance by Frances Karamouzis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UiPath: Unlock the Power of AI in Your Business with Automation with Dottie Dunn, Timothy Kim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Future of AI: Less Talking, More Doing by Erick Brethenoux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While AI dominated the conversation, it was refreshing to hear broader visions of the future and a few key insights that connected AI to the human experience. Here are some of my takeaways from the day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Interview with Jensen Huang: A Visionary Leader in AI Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="Jensen-44f53abe.webp" alt="Jensen" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jensen Huang’s interview was a standout. His advice to move from traditional CPU hardware to GPU-based solutions was compelling, not just for specialized tasks but for everyday computing, highlighting a 20x productivity boost. What struck me most was his emphasis on &lt;em&gt;just getting started&lt;/em&gt;—embracing AI experimentation to drive transformation across industries. Huang’s vision of AI-driven digital workers collaborating alongside human teams was an inspiring take on how AI can reshape work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shift to GPUs&lt;/strong&gt;: Accelerated computing using GPUs can deliver up to 20x productivity gains, even in general computing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Workers&lt;/strong&gt;: A future workforce will include AI agents that assist human employees, particularly in areas like customer service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI for Business&lt;/strong&gt;: AI isn’t just for external applications—use it to enhance internal processes like supply chain management and chip design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leadership in AI&lt;/strong&gt;: Leaders must embrace reinvention, pushing the boundaries of AI to stay relevant and future-proof their organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Gartner’s Top Strategic Predictions for 2025 and Beyond: The AI Whirlwind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="predict-86fc1515.webp" alt="Predict" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daryl Plummer’s talk took a broader look at where AI is headed in the coming years. While there weren’t immediate takeaways for me to implement, it painted a fascinating picture of AI’s expanding influence across industries—from AI agents negotiating contracts to AI-driven healthcare systems detecting emotional states. The session made me think deeply about the ethical considerations of AI, particularly as it continues to blur the lines between human and machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI in Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;: AI is now capable of negotiating contracts, pointing to a future where even high-level business interactions are automated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emotional AI in Healthcare&lt;/strong&gt;: By 2027, emotional AI will play a critical role in detecting patients’ emotional states, potentially improving care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Driven Flattening&lt;/strong&gt;: By 2026, AI could eliminate up to 50% of middle management roles, flattening organizational structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Maverick Research: Being Human 2045&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="new-world-c60a2381.webp" alt="Predict" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty Resnick’s session was my favorite of the day. While AI was part of the conversation, the talk expanded into imaginative realms of space travel, household robots, and the blending of digital and physical worlds. This was more of a visionary exploration than a prescriptive session, which I loved. It painted a hopeful, exciting future—one where AI and robotics could truly transform our lives. Space travel and autonomous systems are becoming more of a reality every year, and the potential for household robots to assist with daily chores is something we may see by 2045.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Household Robots&lt;/strong&gt;: By 2040, 50% of households could have robots assisting with tasks like cleaning or cooking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Space Travel&lt;/strong&gt;: By 2045, 20% of the population may afford annual space vacations, driven by decreasing space travel costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Personhood&lt;/strong&gt;: AI avatars could gain legal rights by 2045, prompting fascinating debates on the future of digital personhood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Future of AI: Less Talking, More Doing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="quote-cb41825f.webp" alt="Predict" class="lazyload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erick Brethenoux took a refreshingly practical approach to AI in his talk. His focus was on simplifying and enhancing human lives, reminding us that AI’s goal should be to free us from tedious tasks, not create additional complexity. I particularly liked his emphasis on starting small—ask your employees what they dislike most about their jobs and see if AI can automate those tasks. This human-first, simplicity-driven approach is something I think is key as we move forward with AI. His comparison to Apple’s minimalist design ethos—where fewer buttons often mean better user experiences—hit home for me as a UX leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human-First AI&lt;/strong&gt;: AI should enhance the human experience, simplifying tasks and making work more enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity Over Complexity&lt;/strong&gt;: Less is more—like Apple’s approach to product design, AI should focus on usability and reducing complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employee-Centric AI&lt;/strong&gt;: Start by automating tasks that employees find tedious, improving job satisfaction and productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Future of AI and UX&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a UX leader, these sessions left me thinking about how AI will shape the future of user experience design. One of the key themes I noticed across the talks was simplicity. Whether it’s Huang’s vision of AI-driven digital workers or Brethenoux’s push for thoughtful AI implementation, the message was clear: AI should enhance, not complicate, the user experience. As we continue to push the boundaries of what AI can do, there’s a great opportunity for UX professionals to ensure that these advancements truly serve human needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One idea I’ve been exploring is the concept of &lt;strong&gt;“AI as a Design Partner,”&lt;/strong&gt; where AI assists in the design process by analyzing user behavior patterns and suggesting design improvements. This could revolutionize how we build user interfaces, allowing designers to focus on the bigger picture while AI handles the tedious but important work of data analysis. It’s an exciting time for UX, and as AI continues to evolve, our role in shaping user-centric, human-first experiences will be more important than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2 at Gartner was packed with insights, and while the AI buzz is undeniable, it’s clear that we’re still in the early stages of truly understanding its potential. What excites me most is not the technology itself, but the human potential it unlocks. Whether it’s simplifying our work, enhancing our lives at home, or taking us to space, AI is poised to transform our world in ways that go beyond what we can imagine today. And as UX leaders, we’ll have a crucial role in ensuring these technologies are designed with the human experience at the center.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
